Guide to the Ost Family Papers TAM.850
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Ost Family Papers
1948-2014
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Ost, Milton
Ost, Ruth
Ost, David
Ost, Fred
TAM.850
.83 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
Milton Ost (1917-1987) and Ruth Ost (1928-2022) were actively engaged in progressive matters throughout their lives, and were members of the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA) until leaving soon after 1956. Milton Ost was a writer who worked in direct mail advertising. Milton wrote skits for CPUSA rallies, as well as a play titled The Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, which was read and performed at left-wing trade union events. Milton also wrote articles for Jewish Currents. Ruth Ost worked on the Management Committee of Jewish Currents, and for 30 years was the Office Manager of Lobsenz-Stevens public relations firm. The Ost Family Papers (dated 1948-2014) consist of materials created and collected by Milton and Ruth Ost documenting their personal lives and political engagements. Materials in this collection include copies of Milton's writings, including a script for The Warsaw Ghetto Uprising; documents from Milton's memorial service at Riverside Memorial Chapel; and photographs from Steve Nelson's 72nd birthday celebration, where he was honored at the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Luncheon. The collection also includes correspondence, including correspondence between Ruth and her sister Faith Bonosky, the wife of Philip Bonosky. Ruth and Faith's letters help document the Bonosky's family life, including the time period that the Bonoskys lived in the USSR. Other correspondents include Henry Foner, Steve Nelson, and friends and family expressing their condolences following Milton's death.
Scope and Contents
The Ost Family Papers (dated 1948-2014) consist of materials created and collected by Milton and Ruth Ost documenting their personal lives and political engagements. Materials in this collection include copies of Milton's writings, including a script for The Warsaw Ghetto Uprising; documents from Milton's memorial service at Riverside Memorial Chapel; and photographs from Steve Nelson's 72nd birthday celebration, where he was honored at the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Luncheon. The collection also includes correspondence, including correspondence between Ruth and her sister Faith Bonosky, the wife of Philip Bonosky. Ruth and Faith's letters help document the Bonosky's family life, including the time period that the Bonoskys lived in the USSR. Other correspondents include Henry Foner, Steve Nelson, and friends and family expressing their condolences following Milton's death. Other materials include ephemera and writings by Bill Mardo, the sports writer for the Daily Worker, Ruth's life partner after Milton's death.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by David and Fred Ost in September 2024; the accession number associated with this gift is 2025.051.
Biographical Note on Milton Ost
Milton Ost (1917-1987) was a writer who worked in direct mail advertising. Ost was a member of the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA) until leaving soon after 1956. Ost wrote skits for CPUSA rallies, as well as a play titled The Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, which was read and performed at left-wing trade union events. Ost also wrote articles for Jewish Currents.
Biographical Note on Ruth Ost
Ruth Ost (1928-2022) was actively engaged in progressive matters throughout her life. She was a member of the Communist Party of the United States (CPUSA) until leaving soon after 1956. She worked on the Management Committee of Jewish Currents, and for 30 years was the Office Manager of Lobsenz-Stevens public relations firm.
Correspondence.; Communism.; Social movements.; Communist Party of the United States of America; Ost, David; Ost, Fred
- Block, Doris, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence -- General, 1965-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
- Correspondence -- Bonosky, Faith, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Correspondence -- Condolences, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence -- Milt's Book, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence -- Nelson, Steve, 1986-2014 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Foner, Henry, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Jewish Currents, 1987-2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mardo, Bill, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
- Milton Ost Memorial Service, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Steve Nelson's Birthday Party -- Photographs, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Poem by Ruth to Milton, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "Roots of Unity", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Start with Flowers End with Trees: A Life of Poetry, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Warsaw Ghetto Uprising Script, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Writings by Milton, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)